<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Driving innovation | Where Ideas Come to Life | Creating innovation together on Technology Blog</title>
    <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/</link>
    <description>Die neuesten Inhalte auf Technology Blog</description>
    
    <language>en</language>
    
    <copyright>Copyright 2025 NTT DATA Deutschland SE - This site does not use any cookies</copyright>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 09:26:55 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://nttdata-dach.github.io/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kong - The Gateway without Limitations - Part 10: AI Gateway</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/as-konggateway-aigateway/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io//posts/img/AS-KongGateway-AiGateway/title-image.jpg</guid>
      <description>This blog details how Kong API Gateway functions as an AI Gateway, providing the necessary features to manage AI integrations securely and efficiently. Kong offers a complete, high-quality middleware solution that makes AI development easier by removing the need for many special tools and frameworks. It also supports language independence to avoid any limits. Additionally, the new AI plugins empower organizations to mitigate AI risks and uphold ethical AI practices.</description>

      
      
        
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kong - The Gateway without Limitations - Part 9: Serverless functions - Who responded?</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/as-konggateway-serverlessfunctions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io//posts/img/AS-KongGateway-ServerlessFunctions/title-image.jpg</guid>
      <description>In our previous blog posts in the Kong Gateway series, we explored various security aspects, particularly focusing on token-related issues and their solutions involving both Kong and custom-built plugins. Today, we dive deeper into another coding variant within the gateway: Kong serverless functions. We will use a real-world “Who Responded?” example to demonstrate how effectively a root cause analysis approach can be supported with minimal effort.</description>

      
      
        
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducible and consistent development environments with DevContainers</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/sk-devcontainers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io//posts/img/SK-DevContainers/title-image.jpg</guid>
      <description>As a developer in an agile world it becomes quite normal to be involved in more than one activity (projects, trainings and some research) at a  time. Each of these activities may require a specific setup of development environments in terms of programming languages, compiler and library versions. Installing and maintaining all this with a classical approach is error-prone and requires a lot of effort. Using task-specific virtual machines would solve the problem, but it consumes a lot of resources and causes a lot of maintenance as well, because one also needs to keep VM&amp;rsquo;s operating system up to date. This article shows, how DevContainers can help you create and maintain reproducible development environments leveraging the benefits of modern container technology.</description>

      
      
        
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kong - The Gateway without Limitations - Part 8: Plugin Cloning</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/as-konggateway-plugincloning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io//posts/img/AS-KongGateway-PluginCloning/title-image.jpg</guid>
      <description>This time we explore how plugin cloning of the Access Control List (ACL) Plugin enhances API security within a zero-trust architecture. We address the challenge of executing the ACL plugin twice, first for a consumer authenticated via an mTLS client certificate and then for a consumer authenticated via an OAuth2 token in the same processing pipeline, as the Kong’s architecture prevents the same plugin from running multiple times in a single request-response cycle. To meet this challenge, we introduce the Kong supported Priority-Updater tool, which enables cloning and priority configuration of existing plugins. This blog provides a comprehensive guide to implementing multi-layer authentication by plugin cloning.</description>

      
      
        
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Performance Optimization</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/fjlm-webperformanceoptimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io//posts/img/FJLM-WebPerformanceOptimization/title-image.jpg</guid>
      <description>In this post, you will learn about the importance of optimizing web page loading times and how it impacts conversions, as well as why it&amp;rsquo;s critical for SEO positioning and visibility. We&amp;rsquo;ll also outline tips and strategies for improving website performance, ranging from website speed tests to image optimization, and minimizing CSS and Javascript among other techniques. Additionally, we discuss important metrics like time to first byte and the benefits of using technologies like HTTP/2 and Gzip compression. This post offers valuable insights into how to improve your website&amp;rsquo;s performance and user experience.</description>

      
      
        
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Flutter CI/CD with Fastlane and GitHub Actions - Part 2: Releases</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/dd-fluttercicd-02-releases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io//posts/img/DD-FlutterCICD-02-Releases/title-image.jpg</guid>
      <description>Let’s continue to automate the release process with versioning, GitHub releases, and promotion using Fastlane and GitHub Actions. This time we focus on setting up a new workflow that bumps the version, creates a new tag, and pushes the changes to the repository. The article also covers creating a new release with generated release notes from the commit messages and merged branches since the last tag. Finally, we will promote a release from the internal track or TestFlight to the production track in the PlayStore and AppStore respectively. All in all, this is an essential guide to streamlining the release process for your Flutter app.</description>

      
      
        
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data streaming with Confluent Kafka Connect</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/jh-confluentkafkaconnect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io//posts/img/JCH-ConfluentKafkaConnect/title-image.jpg</guid>
      <description>Kafka Connect, a solution from Confluent for transferring data to and from Kafka, provides a high-performance and scalable option for connecting to over 80 different data sources, including databases, messaging systems, REST interfaces, and cloud storage. Using Kafka Connect can save a lot of time and effort, especially if scalability and security are important to your project. To use Connect, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to understand the basic architecture, which includes Workers, Tasks and Connectors  as well as how to configure them.</description>

      
      
        
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hazelcast Metrics via Prometheus</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/rd-hazelcastmetricsviaprometheus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io//posts/img/RD-HazelcastMetricsViaPrometheus/title-image.jpg</guid>
      <description>A step-by-step guide on how to collect Hazelcast metrics via Prometheus. The tutorial is aimed at those who are running a customized Hazelcast microservice, rather than the full-blown zip-file/dockers. The guide covers all the necessary steps, from adding the Prometheus dependency to Java code configuration, updating application YAML and Dockerfile, to updating the ServiceMonitor. The article also offers helpful hints and sources for further reading.</description>

      
      
        
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Transitioning from Prometheus to OpenTelemetry - A Journey of a Cluster&#39;s Metrics Evolution - Part 3: Enabling annotation-based scraping</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/mjm-sa-otelmetrics-03-annotationbasedscraping/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io//posts/img/MJM-SA-OtelMetrics-03-AnnotationBasedScraping/title-image.jpg</guid>
      <description>After showing how to get an OpenTelemetry Collector to support Prometheus CRDs as scrape targets, we discover how to integrate another well-known approach to mark workloads as scrape targets. Now, we focus on annotation-based scraping - what is it, when would we want to use it and how can we integrate it in our OpenTelemetry stack? In this article, we provide answers to all these questions, and more.</description>

      
      
        
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Flutter CI/CD with Fastlane and GitHub Actions - Part 1: The Basics</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/dd-fluttercicd-01-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io//posts/img/DD-FlutterCICD-01-Basics/title-image.jpg</guid>
      <description>Automate your Flutter app deployment with this step-by-step guide using Fastlane and GitHub Actions. The article provides the necessary code snippets, for setting up the Fastlane files and environment, defining lanes for deployment to the App Store and Play Store, and automating the process using GitHub Actions. Overall, this article is an essential guide to streamlining the app deployment process, and it&amp;rsquo;s perfect for Flutter developers looking to automate their workflow.</description>

      
      
        
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kong - The Gateway without Limitations - Part 7: Token Cloning</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/as-konggateway-tokencloning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io//posts/img/AS-KongGateway-TokenCloning/title-image.jpg</guid>
      <description>Building on the previous post, we discuss an architectural pattern for token handling called &amp;rsquo;therapeutic token cloning&amp;rsquo;, which is particularly effective in environments that use multiple identity and access management products. The pattern involves duplicating, correcting, and then re-signing access tokens to make them functional and more secure. This article details the steps involved in the token cloning process, as well as the pros and cons of this approach.</description>

      
      
        
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kong - The Gateway without Limitations - Part 6: Token Validation</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/as-konggateway-tokenvalidation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io//posts/img/AS-KongGateway-TokenValidation/title-image.jpg</guid>
      <description>This time we discuss token validation in the context of the Kong Gateway, covering topics such as OpenID Connect, OAuth 2.0, and Zero-Trust Architecture. The article explains the different types of tokens, the benefits of offline validation, and the various Kong plugins that support token validation. The article notes that architectural trade-offs may be required regarding revocation and fine-grained authorization validation, and concludes that Kong Gateway offers ample options for token validation, including the ability to write custom plugins.</description>

      
      
        
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Transitioning from Prometheus to OpenTelemetry - A Journey of a Cluster&#39;s Metrics Evolution - Part 2: Scraping The First Metrics</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/mjm-sa-otelmetrics-02-firstmetrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io//posts/img/MJM-SA-OtelMetrics-02-FirstMetrics/title-image.jpg</guid>
      <description>Having explained the technical implementation of the monitoring stack in our latest blog post, this article focuses on replacing Prometheus with OpenTelemetry Collector to decouple scraping from the storage and query mechanisms. The OpenTelemetry Collector uses various building blocks to construct the telemetry pipeline and requires enabling of the target allocator. Guiding you through this process we provide various practical tips, including processor ordering and horizontal autoscaling.&amp;quot;</description>

      
      
        
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Immersive Technologies - Part 1: Introduction to immersive technologies</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/ss-immersivetechnologies-01-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io//posts/img/SS-ImmersiveTechnologies-01-Basics/title-image.jpg</guid>
      <description>Immersive technologies, alternatively referred to as XR technologies, possess the capability to either augment or replace the physical world with a digitally simulated one. This article provides an overview by describing the three categories of immersive technologies, including relevant background information, and significant use cases.</description>

      
      
        
    </item>
    
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
