<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ZTA on Technology Blog</title>
    <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/tags/zta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ZTA on Technology Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright 2025 NTT DATA Deutschland SE - This site does not use any cookies</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nttdata-dach.github.io/tags/zta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Part 8: Plugin Cloning</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/as-konggateway-plugincloning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/as-konggateway-plugincloning/</guid>
      <description>This time we explore how plugin cloning of the Access Control List (ACL) Plugin enhances API security within a zero-trust architecture. We address the challenge of executing the ACL plugin twice, first for a consumer authenticated via an mTLS client certificate and then for a consumer authenticated via an OAuth2 token in the same processing pipeline, as the Kong’s architecture prevents the same plugin from running multiple times in a single request-response cycle. To meet this challenge, we introduce the Kong supported Priority-Updater tool, which enables cloning and priority configuration of existing plugins. This blog provides a comprehensive guide to implementing multi-layer authentication by plugin cloning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 5: mTLS Header</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/as-konggateway-mtls_header/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/as-konggateway-mtls_header/</guid>
      <description>Mutual transport layer security (mTLS) with consumer authentication using client certificates at the Kong Gateway plays an important role in building a zero-trust architecture. But perimeter security devices that perform TLS termination, so-called TLS terminating reverse proxies (TTRP), break the automatic mapping of client certificates to Kong consumers. This blog demonstrates mTLS consumer authentication even with preceding TTRPs, without requiring TCP passthrough.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
