<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>RFC 9068 on Technology Blog</title>
    <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/tags/rfc-9068/</link>
    <description>Recent content in RFC 9068 on Technology Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright 2025 NTT DATA Deutschland SE - This site does not use any cookies</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nttdata-dach.github.io/tags/rfc-9068/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Part 7: Token Cloning</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/as-konggateway-tokencloning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/as-konggateway-tokencloning/</guid>
      <description>Building on the previous post, we discuss an architectural pattern for token handling called &amp;rsquo;therapeutic token cloning&amp;rsquo;, which is particularly effective in environments that use multiple identity and access management products. The pattern involves duplicating, correcting, and then re-signing access tokens to make them functional and more secure. This article details the steps involved in the token cloning process, as well as the pros and cons of this approach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 6: Token Validation</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/as-konggateway-tokenvalidation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/as-konggateway-tokenvalidation/</guid>
      <description>This time we discuss token validation in the context of the Kong Gateway, covering topics such as OpenID Connect, OAuth 2.0, and Zero-Trust Architecture. The article explains the different types of tokens, the benefits of offline validation, and the various Kong plugins that support token validation. The article notes that architectural trade-offs may be required regarding revocation and fine-grained authorization validation, and concludes that Kong Gateway offers ample options for token validation, including the ability to write custom plugins.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
