<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Clients first on Technology Blog</title>
    <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Clients first on Technology Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright 2025 NTT DATA Deutschland SE - This site does not use any cookies</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reproducible and consistent development environments with DevContainers</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/sk-devcontainers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/sk-devcontainers/</guid>
      <description>As a developer in an agile world it becomes quite normal to be involved in more than one activity (projects, trainings and some research) at a  time. Each of these activities may require a specific setup of development environments in terms of programming languages, compiler and library versions. Installing and maintaining all this with a classical approach is error-prone and requires a lot of effort. Using task-specific virtual machines would solve the problem, but it consumes a lot of resources and causes a lot of maintenance as well, because one also needs to keep VM&amp;rsquo;s operating system up to date. This article shows, how DevContainers can help you create and maintain reproducible development environments leveraging the benefits of modern container technology.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 9: Serverless functions: Who responded?</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/as-konggateway-serverlessfunctions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/as-konggateway-serverlessfunctions/</guid>
      <description>In our previous blog posts in the Kong Gateway series, we explored various security aspects, particularly focusing on token-related issues and their solutions involving both Kong and custom-built plugins. Today, we dive deeper into another coding variant within the gateway: Kong serverless functions. We will use a real-world “Who Responded?” example to demonstrate how effectively a root cause analysis approach can be supported with minimal effort.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 8: Plugin Cloning</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/as-konggateway-plugincloning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/as-konggateway-plugincloning/</guid>
      <description>This time we explore how plugin cloning of the Access Control List (ACL) Plugin enhances API security within a zero-trust architecture. We address the challenge of executing the ACL plugin twice, first for a consumer authenticated via an mTLS client certificate and then for a consumer authenticated via an OAuth2 token in the same processing pipeline, as the Kong’s architecture prevents the same plugin from running multiple times in a single request-response cycle. To meet this challenge, we introduce the Kong supported Priority-Updater tool, which enables cloning and priority configuration of existing plugins. This blog provides a comprehensive guide to implementing multi-layer authentication by plugin cloning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web Performance Optimization</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/fjlm-webperformanceoptimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/fjlm-webperformanceoptimization/</guid>
      <description>In this post, you will learn about the importance of optimizing web page loading times and how it impacts conversions, as well as why it&amp;rsquo;s critical for SEO positioning and visibility. We&amp;rsquo;ll also outline tips and strategies for improving website performance, ranging from website speed tests to image optimization, and minimizing CSS and Javascript among other techniques. Additionally, we discuss important metrics like time to first byte and the benefits of using technologies like HTTP/2 and Gzip compression. This post offers valuable insights into how to improve your website&amp;rsquo;s performance and user experience.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calculating your carbon footprint: a guide to measuring serverless app emissions on AWS</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/fw-da-calculatingyourcarbonfootprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/fw-da-calculatingyourcarbonfootprint/</guid>
      <description>This blog article presents a methodology developed by NTT Data to quantify the carbon emissions of serverless applications on AWS. It examines a Campaign Management System architecture and utilizes tools like the SCI calculator to uncover insights into the relationship between application traffic and carbon emissions. The authors address challenges in metrics availability and data collection within serverless environments and discuss how Green Software Patterns can mitigate environmental impacts. The article highlights the significance of sustainability in serverless computing and lays the groundwork for future advancements in greener cloud solutions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 2: Releases</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/dd-fluttercicd-02-releases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/dd-fluttercicd-02-releases/</guid>
      <description>Let’s continue to automate the release process with versioning, GitHub releases, and promotion using Fastlane and GitHub Actions. This time we focus on setting up a new workflow that bumps the version, creates a new tag, and pushes the changes to the repository. The article also covers creating a new release with generated release notes from the commit messages and merged branches since the last tag. Finally, we will promote a release from the internal track or TestFlight to the production track in the PlayStore and AppStore respectively. All in all, this is an essential guide to streamlining the release process for your Flutter app.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data streaming with Confluent Kafka Connect</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/jh-confluentkafkaconnect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/jh-confluentkafkaconnect/</guid>
      <description>Kafka Connect, a solution from Confluent for transferring data to and from Kafka, provides a high-performance and scalable option for connecting to over 80 different data sources, including databases, messaging systems, REST interfaces, and cloud storage. Using Kafka Connect can save a lot of time and effort, especially if scalability and security are important to your project. To use Connect, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to understand the basic architecture, which includes Workers, Tasks and Connectors  as well as how to configure them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hazelcast Metrics via Prometheus</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/rd-hazelcastmetricsviaprometheus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/rd-hazelcastmetricsviaprometheus/</guid>
      <description>A step-by-step guide on how to collect Hazelcast metrics via Prometheus. The tutorial is aimed at those who are running a customized Hazelcast microservice, rather than the full-blown zip-file/dockers. The guide covers all the necessary steps, from adding the Prometheus dependency to Java code configuration, updating application YAML and Dockerfile, to updating the ServiceMonitor. The article also offers helpful hints and sources for further reading.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 3: Enabling annotation-based scraping</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/mjm-sa-otelmetrics-03-annotationbasedscraping/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/mjm-sa-otelmetrics-03-annotationbasedscraping/</guid>
      <description>After showing how to get an OpenTelemetry Collector to support Prometheus CRDs as scrape targets, we discover how to integrate another well-known approach to mark workloads as scrape targets. Now, we focus on annotation-based scraping - what is it, when would we want to use it and how can we integrate it in our OpenTelemetry stack? In this article, we provide answers to all these questions, and more.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 1: The Basics</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/dd-fluttercicd-01-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/dd-fluttercicd-01-basics/</guid>
      <description>Automate your Flutter app deployment with this step-by-step guide using Fastlane and GitHub Actions. The article provides the necessary code snippets, for setting up the Fastlane files and environment, defining lanes for deployment to the App Store and Play Store, and automating the process using GitHub Actions. Overall, this article is an essential guide to streamlining the app deployment process, and it&amp;rsquo;s perfect for Flutter developers looking to automate their workflow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 7: Token Cloning</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/as-konggateway-tokencloning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/as-konggateway-tokencloning/</guid>
      <description>Building on the previous post, we discuss an architectural pattern for token handling called &amp;rsquo;therapeutic token cloning&amp;rsquo;, which is particularly effective in environments that use multiple identity and access management products. The pattern involves duplicating, correcting, and then re-signing access tokens to make them functional and more secure. This article details the steps involved in the token cloning process, as well as the pros and cons of this approach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 6: Token Validation</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/as-konggateway-tokenvalidation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/as-konggateway-tokenvalidation/</guid>
      <description>This time we discuss token validation in the context of the Kong Gateway, covering topics such as OpenID Connect, OAuth 2.0, and Zero-Trust Architecture. The article explains the different types of tokens, the benefits of offline validation, and the various Kong plugins that support token validation. The article notes that architectural trade-offs may be required regarding revocation and fine-grained authorization validation, and concludes that Kong Gateway offers ample options for token validation, including the ability to write custom plugins.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 2: Scraping The First Metrics</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/mjm-sa-otelmetrics-02-firstmetrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/mjm-sa-otelmetrics-02-firstmetrics/</guid>
      <description>Having explained the technical implementation of the monitoring stack in our latest blog post, this article focuses on replacing Prometheus with OpenTelemetry Collector to decouple scraping from the storage and query mechanisms. The OpenTelemetry Collector uses various building blocks to construct the telemetry pipeline and requires enabling of the target allocator. Guiding you through this process we provide various practical tips, including processor ordering and horizontal autoscaling.&amp;quot;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 1: Introduction to immersive technologies</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/ss-immersivetechnologies-01-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/ss-immersivetechnologies-01-basics/</guid>
      <description>Immersive technologies, alternatively referred to as XR technologies, possess the capability to either augment or replace the physical world with a digitally simulated one. This article provides an overview by describing the three categories of immersive technologies, including relevant background information, and significant use cases.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data mesh as an element of data strategy</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/nf-en-datameshasanelementofdatastrategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/nf-en-datameshasanelementofdatastrategy/</guid>
      <description>In this article we discuss the challenges of storing vast amounts of data to become a value-driven organization and introduce data mesh, an innovative technology that addresses these challenges. We outline the four principles of data mesh and provide a step-by-step framework for implementing the architecture. The article also gives an example of data mesh implementation using serverless tools on AWS and emphasizes that the selection between data mesh and traditional data architectures depends on the specific needs, capabilities, and goals of the business.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 6: Setting Up an Unreal Engine Project: Best Practices for Interactive Immersive Experiences</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/ss-immersivetechnologies-06-settingupunrealproject/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/ss-immersivetechnologies-06-settingupunrealproject/</guid>
      <description>tbd</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 5: mTLS Header</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/as-konggateway-mtls_header/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/as-konggateway-mtls_header/</guid>
      <description>Mutual transport layer security (mTLS) with consumer authentication using client certificates at the Kong Gateway plays an important role in building a zero-trust architecture. But perimeter security devices that perform TLS termination, so-called TLS terminating reverse proxies (TTRP), break the automatic mapping of client certificates to Kong consumers. This blog demonstrates mTLS consumer authentication even with preceding TTRPs, without requiring TCP passthrough.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 4: SAML 2.0 Bearer Assertion Flow for OAuth 2.0</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/as-konggateway-saml2bearer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/as-konggateway-saml2bearer/</guid>
      <description>My last blog provided a solution for implementing an OAuth 2.0-based On-Behalf-Of (delegation) grant flow. This time it’s about implementing a Security Assertion Markup Language (SAML) 2.0 Profile for OAuth 2.0 Client Authentication and Authorization Grants. This flow allows OAuth 2.0 clients to obtain access tokens by presenting SAML 2.0 assertions as a form of authentication. This somewhat extended grant flow expands the scope for exchanging authentication and authorization data between different parties with seamless management, all achieved through the API Gateway.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 1: A Brief Introduction</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/mjm-sa-otelmetrics-01-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/mjm-sa-otelmetrics-01-intro/</guid>
      <description>With this blog post, we kick off a series on evolving our Kubernetes metrics stack. Our journey to replace Prometheus with an OpenTelemetry solution begins with an introduction OpenTelemetry and why we see it as a valid alternative to our current implementation. After explaining the main parts of the OpenTelemetry project and briefly reviewing its history, we discuss the pros and cons. After reading this, you will be able to follow along our hands-on and deep-tech posts on how we optimize our metrics stack.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 3: Token Exchange On-Behalf-Of</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/as-konggateway-onbehalfof/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/as-konggateway-onbehalfof/</guid>
      <description>In the last blog, I provided a solution on how to overcome the character limit when logging. This time, I would like to show how to implement an OAuth 2.0-based On-Behalf-Of (delegation) grant flow. Such complex token orchestration tasks can be easily handled on the API gateway while ensuring the highest security standards which even make zero-trust architectures possible in the first place.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secrets Handling in Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/sk-secretshandlinginkubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/sk-secretshandlinginkubernetes/</guid>
      <description>Committing plain .yaml files which defines Kubernetes secrets definitions to a source code management system is not very secure. This article explains why and shows two better alternatives.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building and running Flutter mobile applications for Android on AWS Device Farm</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/ak-buildingrunningflutteronaws/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/ak-buildingrunningflutteronaws/</guid>
      <description>This article will give you an overview on how to build and run a Flutter cross-platform mobile application for the Android OS platform in the cloud. We will cover all the steps from the basic app itself to the integration with Appium, and ultimately the deployment and testing on several devices in the AWS Device Farm.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 2: Log Chunking</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/as-konglogchunking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/as-konglogchunking/</guid>
      <description>In the last blog, I briefly introduced Kong as a sophisticated API gateway product. This time, I will discuss a problem related to logging message size limitation and offer a solution. This problem significantly limits root cause analysis and ultimately solution development.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Renovate to scale up automatic pull request creation on GitHub</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/mjm-renovateautomaticpullrequest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/mjm-renovateautomaticpullrequest/</guid>
      <description>See how we use the dependency update tool Renovate to distribute helm charts with ArgoCD applications in a GitOps fashion. This article shows how to set up Renovate for several kubernetes clusters with a centralized configuration as a GitHub action.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 1: Introduction to Crossplane</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/ns-controlplaneoperatedinfrastructure_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/ns-controlplaneoperatedinfrastructure_1/</guid>
      <description>This tech blog article introduces Crossplane, an open-source Kubernetes add-on that extends the capabilities of infrastructure management by leveraging Kubernetes as a control plane. Crossplane uses Kubernetes&amp;rsquo; extensible API design and Custom Resource Definitions (CRDs) to manage not only services and applications but also cloud infrastructure. The article provides step-by-step instructions on how to get started with Crossplane and provision your first resources in the cloud using Kubernetes as a control plane.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 6: Setting Up a Unreal Engine Project - Best Practices for Interactive Immersive Experiences</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/ss-settingupanunrealproject/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/ss-settingupanunrealproject/</guid>
      <description>tbd</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 1: Brief Product Introduction</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/as-kongproductintroduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/as-kongproductintroduction/</guid>
      <description>Kong Gateway is a lightweight, fast, and flexible API Gateway. It acts as an intermediary between API providers and consumers, enabling them to communicate based on policies. It also provides observability features, allowing to track API usage and performance. Overall it is a convincing and outstanding product which is briefly introduced in the following blog.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Random Generators in Java 17</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/ms-newrandomgeneratorsinjava17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/ms-newrandomgeneratorsinjava17/</guid>
      <description>Java 17 introduced new random number generators. These provide longer cycles, improved statistical uniform distribution, improved threading support, and Streams API integration. This article provides a short introduction to random number generators and an overview of the improvements made in Java 17.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 2: Tools in your arsenal</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/ab_softwaresupplychainsecurity_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/ab_softwaresupplychainsecurity_2/</guid>
      <description>In the first part we discussed software supply chain in general, which possible attack vectors exist and what actions are being taken by the community but rather in an isolated manner. In this part, I&amp;rsquo;ll line out specific actions which can be taken in an organized manner and which tools/framework/guidelines can be useful along this way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 1: Attack vectors</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/ab_softwaresupplychainsecurity_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/ab_softwaresupplychainsecurity_1/</guid>
      <description>There is generally a lot less awareness of Software Supply Chain Security in the contemporary IT landscape and thus its aspects are completely ignored by DevSecOps practices. In this two-part article, I aim to provide an overview of what software supply chain is, what attack vectors you render yourself vulnerable to when not including these aspects in your pipelines and how you can &lt;strong&gt;reduce your attack surface area&lt;/strong&gt; using various tools / frameworks / guidelines like &lt;strong&gt;SLSA&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;sigstore&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;in-toto&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;SBOM&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;TUF&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;OpenSSF&lt;/strong&gt; etc. We will also shed light on how the open source community as a whole is combating this threat.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Completely New Approach: An ECS Programming Language</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/sh-dataorienteddesignecs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/sh-dataorienteddesignecs/</guid>
      <description>Current enterprise software engineering is all about abstraction. We are bending our software in ways that the computer has trouble efficiently computing it. A decade ago we had to write efficient programs, because our hardware was a limiting factor. However, having better hardware is in no excuse to waste precious ressources. With Data-Oriented Design - DOD and Entity Component System - ECS, we can improve performance by up to 100 times!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum-inspired approaches to the Job-Shop Problem</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/mf-sw-jobshopproblem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/mf-sw-jobshopproblem/</guid>
      <description>The Job-Shop problem is a well-known optimization problem where a certain number of jobs have to be scheduled such that the total time needed to finish all jobs is minimal. In this article we shine a light on two algorithms that could be used as a possible solution for this problem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three use cases highlighting the business value of private blockchain</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/ms-usecasesprivateblockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/ms-usecasesprivateblockchain/</guid>
      <description>Rarely do we find a technology as controversial as blockchain. It seems there are as many blockchain sceptics as blockchain enthusiasts. The sceptics are concerned with unlawful behavior that occurred in public blockchain networks, as well as with extremely high current or past energy consumption of certain public blockchains.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accessing private resources on AWS</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/yk-accessingprivateressourcesonaws/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/yk-accessingprivateressourcesonaws/</guid>
      <description>There are several ways to access private resources (located in private subnets within your VPC) on AWS. Let us discuss solutions based on Systems Manger (SSM) and SSH.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pace Predictor</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/ok-pacepredictor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/ok-pacepredictor/</guid>
      <description>At NTT DATA, some of us are sporty spices and we like to record our running, cycling, and swimming in this Strava Club. And of course trail running is also growing very popular in our club.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Container Images Dockerless and Rootless with Buildah</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/ab-containerrootlessbuildah/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/ab-containerrootlessbuildah/</guid>
      <description>“You cannot use Docker in our enterprise CI platform, now way! It needs root rights, thus is not secure; forget it!”, said our DevOps Chief some months ago… So we had a problem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personal Information Integration</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/ok-personalinformationintegration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/ok-personalinformationintegration/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to the internet we have access to a virtually unlimited amount of information. But thanks to the internet we also feel that we are drowning in this information tsunami.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Lessons learnt from large-scale data migration projects</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/ok-lessonsdatamigration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/ok-lessonsdatamigration/</guid>
      <description>Data migration is of course only one aspect of system conversion. Usually data migration is performed in conjunction with other conversions like technology or interfaces. Nevertheless, data migration is often the most expensive and confusing part of the conversion project. So let’s revisit the handful of fairly large data migrations I encountered in my professional career and see which lessons can be drawn out of this experience.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
