<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aws on Technology Blog</title>
    <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/tags/aws/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aws on Technology Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright 2025 NTT DATA Deutschland SE - This site does not use any cookies</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nttdata-dach.github.io/tags/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Secrets Handling in Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/sk-secretshandlinginkubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/sk-secretshandlinginkubernetes/</guid>
      <description>Committing plain .yaml files which defines Kubernetes secrets definitions to a source code management system is not very secure. This article explains why and shows two better alternatives.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building and running Flutter mobile applications for Android on AWS Device Farm</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/ak-buildingrunningflutteronaws/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/ak-buildingrunningflutteronaws/</guid>
      <description>This article will give you an overview on how to build and run a Flutter cross-platform mobile application for the Android OS platform in the cloud. We will cover all the steps from the basic app itself to the integration with Appium, and ultimately the deployment and testing on several devices in the AWS Device Farm.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Part 1: Introduction to Crossplane</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/ns-controlplaneoperatedinfrastructure_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/ns-controlplaneoperatedinfrastructure_1/</guid>
      <description>This tech blog article introduces Crossplane, an open-source Kubernetes add-on that extends the capabilities of infrastructure management by leveraging Kubernetes as a control plane. Crossplane uses Kubernetes&amp;rsquo; extensible API design and Custom Resource Definitions (CRDs) to manage not only services and applications but also cloud infrastructure. The article provides step-by-step instructions on how to get started with Crossplane and provision your first resources in the cloud using Kubernetes as a control plane.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accessing private resources on AWS</title>
      <link>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/yk-accessingprivateressourcesonaws/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://nttdata-dach.github.io/posts/yk-accessingprivateressourcesonaws/</guid>
      <description>There are several ways to access private resources (located in private subnets within your VPC) on AWS. Let us discuss solutions based on Systems Manger (SSM) and SSH.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
